smokingapples.com 2015-04-19

# Privacy Policy

Privacy Policy for Smoking Apples (http://smokingapples.com)

If you require any more information or have any questions about our privacy policy, please feel free to contact us by email at pr@smokingapples.com.

At [Smoking Apples](http://smokingapples.com/), the privacy of our visitors is of extreme importance to us. This privacy policy document outlines the types of personal information is received and collected by Smoking Apples and how it is used.

**Log Files**  
Like many other Web sites, http://smokingapples.com makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol ( IP ) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider ( ISP ), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses, and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable.

**Cookies**  
Smoking Apples does use cookies to store information about visitors preferences, record user-specific information on which pages the user access or visit, customize Web page content based on visitors browser type or other information that the visitor sends via their browser. Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. Our advertising partners include Google Adsense, Amazon.

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on Smoking Apples send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies ( such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons ) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and / or to personalize the advertising content that you see.

Smoking Apples has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. Smoking Apples’s privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites.

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers’ respective websites.

**Security and Notification**  
Because no data transmission over the Internet is completely secure, and no system of physical or electronic security is impenetrable, Service Provider can not guarantee the security of the information you send to us or the security of our servers or databases, and by using the Website you agree to assume all risk in connection with the information sent to us or collected by us when you use the Website. In the unlikely event that we believe that the security of your information in our possession or control may have been compromised, we may seek to notify you. If notification is appropriate, we may notify you by e-mail (provided we have your e-mail address).

Smoking Apples documents all IP addresses that access our website, logged with the urls accessed and the date and time stamps. We also store all comments and the email addresses associated with them for security reasons.

**Email addresses**  
Your email addresses are guaranteed safe with us. Under no circumstances will we reveal your email IDs to anyone unless legally required to. We will never send any advertising or soliciting via email. We generally do not contact users unless specifically asked to in the comments. We might send an email to a specific user to offer personalised help with a certain problem.

We will of course reveal any information, including IP addresses and email IDs, as and when legally required by a court of law. And considering that we’re just a technology blog, the possibilities of that happening are bleak!

If however you still don’t want us to have access to your email, you can very well enter anything that resembles an email and the comments form will accept it. 

**DoubleClick DART cookies**  
We also may use DART cookies for ad serving through Google’s DoubleClick, which places a cookie on your computer when you are browsing the web and visit a site using DoubleClick advertising (including some Google AdSense advertisements). This cookie is used to serve ads specific to you and your interests (”interest based targeting”). The ads served will be targeted based on your previous browsing history (For example, if you have been viewing sites about visiting Las Vegas, you may see Las Vegas hotel advertisements when viewing a non-related site, such as on a site about hockey). DART uses “non personally identifiable information”. It does NOT track personal information about you, such as your name, email address, physical address, telephone number, social security numbers, bank account numbers or credit card numbers. You can opt-out of this ad serving on all sites using this advertising by visiting http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/.

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use information (not including your name, address email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. 

You can chose to disable or selectively turn off our cookies or third-party cookies in your browser settings. However, this can affect how you are able to interact with our site as well as other websites. 

Deleting cookies does not mean you are permanently opted out of any advertising program. Unless you have settings that disallow cookies, the next time you visit a site running the advertisements, a new cookie will be added.

You can also opt out of some third-party vendor’s use of cookies for interest-based advertising by visiting http://www.aboutads.info/

**Disclaimer**  
Our products, advices, opions and reviews are provided “as is” without warranty of any kind, either expressed or implied. In no event shall we be liable for any damages including, but not limited to, direct, indirect, special, incidental or consequential damages or other losses arising out of the use of or inability to use our products.
